<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:sparkle="http://www.andymatuschak.org/xml-namespaces/sparkle"> 
  <channel>
    <title>MacVim Cutting Edge</title>
    <link>http://bjorn.winckler.googlepages.com/macvim_latest.xml</link>
    <description>Most recent changes with links to updates.</description>

    <!--
    To add a new release:

    * add a new <item> below (copy an old one)
    * Adapt the <title>
    * Adapt the <description>
    * Adapt the <pubDate> (format 'Day, dd Mon yyyy hh:mm CET')
    * Adapte <enclosure>, make sure to update the url, length, saprkle:version
      and sparkle:shortVersionString attributes.

    Sparkle honors the following user defaults:

    * SUFeedURL overrides the value in Info.plist (if we want to offer several
      appcasts in the preferences one day ("latest", "stable" for example).

      This means that for testing you can do

          defaults read org.vim.MacVim SUFeedURL  # note this down
          defaults write org.vim.MacVim SUFeedURL file:///Users/you/testcast.xml
            # !!! note the three '/' after 'file:
          # test test test
          defaults write org.vim.MacVim SUFeedURL previousvalue
          # or, to use some default setting for the url,
          defaults delete org.vim.MacVim SUFeedURL

    Sparkle usually assumes a naming scheme of name_versionnumber.tar.bz2 .
    Instead, you can also provide a sparkle:version="2.0_rc2" attribute on
    the enclosure and name the package as you like. You can (and should) also
    provide a sparkle:shortVersionString="User-facing version string"
    attribute that corresponds to CFBundleShortVersionString. Sparkle uses
    CFBundleVersion to determine the current application version.

    Sparkle supports updates in zip, tar, tbz, tgz, or dmg format.
    -->

    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 43 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 43 released</h1>

<p><b>The automatic updating feature is broken in snapshots 39 and 40.  If the automatic updating never finishes extracting then you are affected by this bug and will have to upgrade manually.  To do so, simply go to the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/macvim/wiki/Snapshot">Snapshot page</a> to download the latest version.</b></p>

<p> Changes since snapshot 42:
  <ul>
    <li> Do inclusive search when opening files (Jonathon Mah) </li>
    <li> Respect layout prefs when double-clicking an already open file </li>
    <li> Fix two minor memory leaks </li>
    <li> Ctrl-] works on German keyboard layout </li>
    <li> The .viminfo file is written on Cmd-q </li>
    <li> New 16x16 icons (Nico Weber) </li>
    <li> Untitled window again opens on reopen event if requested in prefs </li>
    <li> Fork earlier; fixes bug with 'autochdir', faster startup, "f" no longer supported in 'guioptions' </li>
    <li> Some other minor bug fixes </li>
    <li> Use latest runtime files and Vim patches </li>
  </ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 13:49 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://newmacvim.muskokamug.org/mirror/files/MacVim-snapshot-43.tbz"
        length="8136440"
        sparkle:version="43"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.2"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 42 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 42 released</h1>

<p><b>The automatic updating feature is broken in snapshots 39 and 40.  If the automatic updating never finishes extracting then you are affected by this bug and will have to upgrade manually.  To do so, simply go to the <a href="http://code.google.com/p/macvim/wiki/Snapshot">Snapshot page</a> to download the latest version.</b></p>

<p> Changes since snapshot 40:
  <ul>
    <li> The menu bar behaves better when using full-screen and switching Spaces (Nico Weber) </li>
    <li> Don't switch Spaces when using "mvim" on one Space and a MacVim window is open on another Space </li>
    <li> Add user default to toggle the "add tab" button on the tabline (to disable, enter "defaults org.vim.MacVim MMShowAddTabButton 0" in Terminal) </li>
    <li> Avoid the "Press ENTER..." prompt when dragging and dropping </li>
    <li> Faster startup (and shutdown, but you're not likely to notice that unless you are me ;-) </li>
    <li> Automatic updating works again </li>
    <li> Possible to interrupt external commands (e.g. you can Ctrl-C during a lenghty :grep now) </li>
    <li> The output from external commands is displayed "interactively" (i.e. you don't have to wait for the command to finish before any output is drawn; try ":!ls -l /usr/lib" and compare with snap 40 to see what I mean) </li>
    <li> Cmd-. sends SIGINT (so that if a Vim process is stuck you should always be able to interrupt it with Cmd-. even if Ctrl-C doesn't work) </li>
    <li> Fix crashing bug: e.g. with snap 40 if you go to the src/ folder of Vim and type ":grep a *.c" MacVim would crash </li>
    <li> Toggle loading of default font with user default MMLoadDefaultFont </li>
  </ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jan 2009 16:12 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://newmacvim.muskokamug.org/mirror/files/MacVim-snapshot-42.tbz"
        length="8131516"
        sparkle:version="42"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.2"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 40 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 40 released</h1>

<p> Changes since snapshot 39:
  <ul>
    <li> Fix problems with Quickstart "leaking" Vim processes </li>
    <li> 'imdisable' now on by default (i.e. IM is disabled by default) </li>
    <li> Clipboard support in non-GUI mode (Kent Sibilev) </li>
    <li> New document icons, more filetype associations (Nico Weber) </li>
    <li> Add support for 'guitabtooltip' (hint: add the line "set gtl=%t gtt=%F" to your .gvimrc to make tabs display the name of the file and have the tooltip display the full path) (Jonathon Mah) </li>
    <li> Look for toolbar icons in runtime path (plugins such as TVO now display toolbar icons properly) </li>
    <li> Show dialog when clicking to close tab with modified buffers </li>
    <li> Update documentation </li>
    <li> Latest runtime files, and Vim patches </li>
  </ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2008 17:26 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://newmacvim.muskokamug.org/mirror/files/MacVim-snapshot-40.tbz"
        length="8138981"
        sparkle:version="40"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.2"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 39 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 39 released</h1>

<p> Changes since snapshot 36 (snapshots 37 and 38 were skipped):
  <ul>
    <li> Avoid "Stray process..." warning messages (Ben Schmidt) </li>
    <li> Add Cmd-BackSpace and Alt-BackSpace insert mode mappings (Nico Weber) </li>
    <li> Dropping multiple files on a window no longer results in an error </li>
    <li> Fix "Login shell" problems (Ben Schmidt) </li>
    <li> Exit Vim process if connection becomes invalid -- this should avoid the system log filling up with error messages, but please let me know when it happens (and send me the output from Console.app) </li>
    <li> Fix bug where Vim would crash when resizing a window with double-width characters </li>
    <li> Add option 'macmeta' to use "alt/option" as meta key to allow bindings to &lt;M-..&gt; (see ":h 'macmeta') </li>
    <li> Add basic support for AppleScript (Jason Foreman).  E.g. to zoom a window:
<pre>
tell application MacVim
    set zoomed of first window to true
end tell
</pre>
    </li>
    <li> Fix various bugs relating to initial window positioning  </li>
    <li> Keep window is visible on ":set lines=..." and "set columns=..." </li>
    <li> Inserting text from "Special Characters" palette works again </li>
    <li> Remove the functionality to use a modifier key as Esc (use the PCKeyboardHack app instead, see ":h macvim-hints | /esc") </li>
    <li> More help on keyboard shortcuts (":h macvim-shortcuts") and the mvim script (see ":h mvim") </li>
    <li> Speed up live resize </li>
    <li> Support mvim script symlinks to [m|g]ex and rmvim (see ":h mvim") </li>
    <li> Tentative support for receiving input from system services (Try this: insert "2+3", select the text, then hit Cmd-*.  Result: "2+3" is replaced with "5".  Sometimes it seems you have to choose "MacVim-&gt;Services-&gt;Script Editor-&gt;Get Result of AppleScript" instead of pressing Cmd-* for this to work.) </li>
    <li> No more Vim zombie processes </li>
    <li> Add "Reload"/"Ignore All" buttons to the file changed dialog </li>
    <li>  Latest runtime files, and Vim patches </li>
  </ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2008 18:09 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://newmacvim.muskokamug.org/mirror/files/MacVim-snapshot-39.tbz"
        length="8012682"
        sparkle:version="39"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.2"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 36 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 36 released</h1>

<p> This snapshot fixes a problem with dropped characters that was introduced with snapshot 35. Other changes since snapshot 35: 
  <ul>
    <li> More help file updates </li>
    <li> Fixed memory leak (Jonathon Mah) </li>
    <li> Tool tips for truncated tab labels (Jonathon Mah) </li>
    <li> Support drag and drop on tabs and on tabline (Jonathon Mah) </li>
    <li> Modifier key can be used as Esc (useful for turning Caps Lock into Esc, see ":h macvim-esc") </li>
    <li> Added "Find & Replace" dialog box (Cmd-f) </li>
  </ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2008 18:38 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://newmacvim.muskokamug.org/mirror/files/MacVim-snapshot-36.tbz"
        length="8005820"
        sparkle:version="36"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.2"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 35 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 35 released</h1>

<p> With this snapshot I have focused on making MacVim faster, fixing bugs, and updating the documentation.  As a result MacVim now feels snappier, flickers less, takes less time to startup from Terminal, and in some cases there are tremendous speed increases. </p>

<p> Here is a summary of the changes since snapshot 34:
<ul>
  <li> Faster startup times </li>
  <li> Overall faster drawing </li>
  <li> Quicker response to key presses </li>
  <li> Fix bug where key presses were ignored when mouse was moved simultaneously </li>
  <li> Update ":h macvim" docs </li>
  <li> Add mvim:// URL handler support (Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> The VimLeave autocommand works with :maca (see ":h macvim-hints") </li>
  <li> Multiple files opened from Finder are sorted </li>
  <li> Don't shift new windows downwards if they are vertically maximized </li>
  <li> Add option to hide MacVim when last window closes </li>
  <li> The "Save changes" dialog conforms to the Apple HIG (works with Cmd-D) </li>
  <li> Fix problems with 'fullscreen' and :mksession (Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> Cmd-e copies selection to Find Pasteboard without searching </li>
  <li> Fix bug with blurry text in full-screen with ATSUI (Jjgod Jiang) </li>
  <li> Cmd-. can be used to interrupt Vim (and to exit insert mode) </li>
  <li> Add "New Document Here" system service (Ron Olson) </li>
  <li> Simplify system services menu (honors the "Open files..." pref) </li>
  <li> Full-screen background color is updated immediately when 'fuopt' changes </li>
  <li> Cursor no longer escapes the command line on Cmd-=/Cmd-- </li>
  <li> Add Input Manager support to ATSUI renderer (Kaoru Yoshida) </li>
  <li> Use latest Vim source code and runtime files </li>
  <li> Minor bug fixes </li>
</ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2008 20:29 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://newmacvim.muskokamug.org/mirror/files/MacVim-snapshot-35.tbz"
        length="7986836"
        sparkle:version="35"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.2"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 34 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 34 released</h1>

<p> Notice that there are now two prebuilt binaries of MacVim: a stable build and the snapshot build.  The snapshot build will be updated fairly often whereas the stable build will not.  If you want to use the stable build you will have to download it manually from <a href="http://code.google.com/p/macvim">http://code.google.com/p/macvim</a>.</p>

<p> This snapshot is based on the recently released Vim 7.2 and it contains some new features and bug fixes.  Here's a partial list of changes since snapshot 33:

<ul>
  <li> More options on how new files should open (in tabs/splits/etc.): Open the preferences to check this out. </li>
  <li> Quickstart: With this feature enabled new windows open instantaneously (but _not_ if you use the 'mvim' script).  It is disabled by default so go to the Advanced preferences to enable it (and be sure to read the "disclaimer"...note that any changes to ~/.vim or its subdirectories are automatically detected on Leopard). </li>
  <li> The ATSUI renderer has received a few bug fixes and it now includes mouse support (it can be enabled in the Advanced prefs).  (bug fixes by Jjgod Jiang) </li>
  <li> Some of the old toolbar icons have been resurrected. </li>
  <li> The current directory is handled more consistently: New windows always have the user's home directory set as current.  Opening a file in the Finder results in the current directory being set to the directory the file is in (unless the file opened in a window with other files already open). </li>
  <li> Windows opened from the Dock menu are in focus. </li>
  <li> Menu item to toggle the Plug-in drawer (Matt Tolton). </li>
  <li> Now possible to set 'linespace' in [g]vimrc. </li>
  <li> Help file cleanup (Michael Wookey). </li>
  <li> Problems with ptys on Leopard fixed (Ben Schmidt). </li>
  <li> (Hopefully) no more annoying "dropping incoming DO message ..." warnings. </li>
  <li> Scroll wheel (track pad) should behave better with fast machines (Issue 100) </li>
  <li> Various bug fixes...
</ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2008 16:59 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://newmacvim.muskokamug.org/mirror/files/MacVim-snapshot-34.tbz"
        length="7959893"
        sparkle:version="34"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.2"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 33 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 33 released</h1>

<p> This snapshot includes contributions from three new MacVim developers: Kyle Lippincott has added support for proxy icons, Matt Tolton has implemented a Plug-In architecture, and Kaoru Yoshida has rewritten the Input Manager support.  Let me just say that I find it very encouraging to get more help with this project!  While we're on the topic of MacVim development; if you are interested in getting started with the source code you should take a look at the newly updated file "src/MacVim/README".  I have also written some documentation on how to contribute with patches using Git, see <a href="http://code.google.com/p/macvim/wiki/Contributing">here</a>.

<p> If you want to get started with plug-in development you should take a look at the example plug-in (FileBrowser.tgz) that Matt posted to vim_mac (the thread is called "Initial Plugin Architecture patch").  I'm sure Matt will be happy to help out with any question you may have (as will I). </p>

<p> I think that the new Input Manager support is a big improvement, but we need feedback from more IM users to let us know exactly how well it works.  Kaoru seems to be on top of fixing bugs as they are reported, so if you have any problems or comments please make yourself heard. </p>

<p> More changes since snapshot 32:
<ul>
  <li> The file open dialog has a check-box to show hidden files (patch by Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> Cmd-? now works </li>
  <li> Partial printing support: Cmd-p opens up Preview.app (Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> Uses Vim 7.2a BETA source code </li>
  <li> Latest runtime files </li>
  <li> Minor bug fixes (see <a href="http://repo.or.cz/w/MacVim.git">here</a>) </li>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2008 20:14 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-33.tbz"
        length="8467287"
        sparkle:version="33"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 32 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 32 released</h1>

<p><em> This snapshot contains fixes for several severe bugs; I strongly suggest
that you update now! </em></p>

<p> Changes since snapshot 31:
<ul>
  <li> Fix several bugs that caused MacVim to crash </li>
  <li> Console dialogs work once again (set go+=c) </li>
  <li> Background processes work (:! ... &) (fix by Ben Schmidt)</li>
  <li> Ctrl-Shift can be used for modeless selection </li>
  <li> No crashes with HTML plugin </li>
  <li> Toolbar is a bit better at finding icons (this still needs some work)
       </li>
  <li> Latest Vim source code and runtime files merged </li>
</ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2008 13:13 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-32.tbz"
        length="8194915"
        sparkle:version="32"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 31 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 31 released</h1>
<p> Changes since snapshot 30:
<ul>
  <li> Fixed problems with menus on OS X 10.4 and a related crash. </li>
  <li> Dialog box handling has been updated.  This fixes a problem where the
       "swap file warning" dialog would pop up before the informational text in
       the editor window updated.  Hopefully this will also cure various other
       problems with dialogs (e.g. nothing happening when opening files from a
       dialog box). </li>
  <li> Added dock menu with "New Window" item.  This is useful with "Spaces" on
       OS X 10.5 since you can use this menu to open a new MacVim window on any
       "space" when another editor window is already open.  (Also, now there is
       always a way to open a new window, even if the menus are customized,
       or if "-u NONE" is used.) </li>
  <li> I have started trying to fix "modeless selection" and it sort of works
       on my machine, but I've had one report stating that its not quite
       working so you mileage may vary.  Make sure to let me know what works
       and doesn't so that I can fix this properly.  (Try selecting text from
       the command line.) </li>
  <li> The default font (DejaVu Sans Mono) has been updated to version 2.25.
  </li>
  <li> Latest Vim source code merged </li>
</ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2008 16:00 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-31.tbz"
        length="8182620"
        sparkle:version="31"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 30 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 30 released</h1>
<p> Changes since snapshot 28:
<ul>
  <li> copy&paste and other "Edit" menu items now work as expected with dialogs
       (such as open/save). </li>
  <li> some menus (such as the "Window" menu) has got some new items </li>
  <li> general menu improvements when no editor window is open </li>
  <li> ability to access some OS X default Cmd-keys even if menus are
       completely altered (e.g. when starting with "-u NONE") </li>
  <li> QuickLook works with .vim files (patch by Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> insert mode cursor honors the 'rightleft' option </li>
  <li> no more "freezes" during :shell </li>
  <li> no beeping on Cmd-q </li>
  <li> Cmd-w works in full-screen again </li>
  <li> window dimensions properly restored when leaving full-screen when
       "maxvert" is in 'fuoptions' </li>
  <li> support for 'mousehide' option </li>
  <li> latest vim patches and runtime files </li>
</ul>
</p>
<p> The only difference between snapshot 29 and 30 is that the former did not
handle window cycling very well with international keyboard layouts. </p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 8 Jun 2008 16:43 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-30.tbz"
        length="8137308"
        sparkle:version="30"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 28 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 28 released</h1>
<p><em>The ":macmenukey" command is now deprecated.  Please update your .gvimrc
file to use the ":macmenu" command instead (if you use ":macmenukey").</em></p>

<p> Changes since snapshot 27:
<ul>
  <li> Added the ":macmenu" commmand (see ":h macmenu") and deprecated
       ":macmenukey"</li>
  <li> Cmd-w now works even when mappings to &lt;-\&gt; are present </li>
  <li> Added "File.Save All" menu item (Cmd-Alt-s) </li>
  <li> The Logitech Control Center no longer causes any problems </li>
  <li> "Edit" menu items now work better with open and save dialogs </li>
  <li> The 'backspace' option now includes "indent,eol,start" by default </li>
  <li> Open and save dialogs track the present working directory </li>
</ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 May 2008 19:40 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-28.tbz"
        length="8124499"
        sparkle:version="28"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 27 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 27 released</h1>
<p> This is the first snapshot compiled on the new Mac I bought with money
    donated from MacVim users!  There were problems with compiling universal
    binaries with Ruby and Perl support on PPC/Tiger so I was hoping to be able
    to include these now that I have Intel/Leopard.  The good news is that Ruby
    support is now included, but Perl still is problematic and I had to drop
    TCL support.  I will try to get these working in a future snapshot.
    </p>

<p> Here is the list of changes since snapshot 26:
<ul>
  <li> 'fuoptions' now support setting the background color while in
       full-screen mode, check ":h 'fuopt'" (patch by Enno Lübbers) </li>
  <li> &lt;D-w&gt; shows confirmation dialog when buffer is modified </li>
  <li> setting 'antialias' from gvimrc now works </li>
  <li> zooming a window no longer causes it to move downwards </li>
  <li> the File menu now contains a "Recent Files" submenu; note that only
       files opened from Finder or with the ":browse" command are added to this
       list, and not files opened with e.g. ":e" (patch by Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> includes latest Vim patches and runtime files </li>
</ul>
</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2008 22:05 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-27-fixed.tbz"
        length="8102568"
        sparkle:version="27"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 26 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 26 released</h1>
<p> This snapshot contains a fix to the bug which caused the first window to
    open in the wrong position as well as an initial version of the new MacVim
    icon.  </p>

      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2008 20:37 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-26.tbz"
        length="8147362"
        sparkle:version="26"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 25 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 25 released</h1>

<p> This snapshot adds support for two new options: 'antialias' and
'fuoptions'.  The former lets you turn text antialiasing on or off (it's
on by default), the latter can be used to make the view maximize when
full-screen is entered.  See the built-in help for more information (:h
'anti' and :h 'fuopt'). </p>

<p> Another minor addition is that &lt;C-c&gt; and &lt;C-v&gt; work with
block-wise selections (do note that &lt;C-v&gt; behaves like "P", not "p").
Also, &lt;D-w&gt; now works in ex-mode and in a command-line window. </p>

<p> Here is the list of changes since snapshot 24:
<ul>
  <li> support 'antialias' option (Jjgod Jiang) </li>
  <li> add option 'fuoptions' to control resizing when full-screen is entered
      (Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> fixed bug where transparency setting was lost after leaving full-screen
      (Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> help menu contains MacVim help and website link </li>
  <li> &lt;D-w&gt; now works in ex-mode and in command-line window </li>
  <li> :macaction command supports command-line completion (Nico Weber) </li>
  <li> copy/paste respects block selections (requested by George Harker) </li>
  <li> window no longer cascades from preferences panel </li>
</ul>
</p>

      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2008 19:11 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-25.tbz"
        length="8042440"
        sparkle:version="25"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 24 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 24 released</h1>

<p><em> The input manager bundled with snapshot 23 contained a bug which could
lead to other apps crashing on startup.  If you have installed the input
manager, then you are strongly advised to update now and install the new input
manager (via the Integration preference pane). </em></p>

<p> Changes since snapshot 23:
<ul>
  <li> The mouse cursor has higher contrast in insert mode (when bg=dark). </li>
  <li> The layout of the Integration preference pane has been updated. </li>
</ul>
</p>

      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2008 20:44 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-24.tbz"
        length="8036815"
        sparkle:version="24"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 23 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 23 released</h1>

Changes since snapshot 22:

<ul>
  <li> The preferences panel has been updated with an "Integration pane".  This
      can be used to easily install (and uninstall) the "Edit in ODBEditor"
      input manager.  The input manager enables you to use MacVim to edit text
      in any Cocoa text field (e.g. you can use MacVim to edit emails in Mail).
      Please read the warning on the Integration pane before installing the
      input manager.  (Patch by Nico Weber.) </li>
  <li> The "Login Shell" preference has been updated so it should now work with
      most shells.  This option ensures that environment variables (e.g. $PATH)
      are set properly.  You should enable it if you ever need to issue shell
      commands from within MacVim.  (Patch by Ben Schmidt.) </li>
  <li> Added MMZoomBoth user default.  Enable this if you prefer the window to
      maximize in both directions when you press the green "maximize button"
      (hold down Cmd to temporarily restrict resizing to the vertical direction
      only).  (Requested by Brian McKee.) </li>
  <li> Added Cmd-Ctrl-z as key equivalent for "Window->Zoom" (this is the same
      key equivalent as in iTunes) </li>
  <li> The Vim runtime files have been updated to the latest version </li>
  <li> MacVim recognizes files with .patch and .diff extension </li>
  <li> The mouse cursor in insert mode has higher contrast (when used with dark
      backgrounds).  (Requested by Enno et al.) </li>
  <li> Line numbers (:h 'number') are brighter when bakground=dark.  (Requested
      by Ted Pavlic) </li>
</ul>

<p>
  Like MacVim?  Go to <a href="http://code.google.com/p/macvim/">
      http://code.google.com/p/macvim/</a> to see how you can show your
  support.
</p>

      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 9 Mar 2008 16:43 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-23.tbz"
        length="8037899"
        sparkle:version="23"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 22 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 22 released</h1>

<p><em>This snapshot replaces the broken snapshot 21.  If you installed build 21
  then please update immediately.</em></p>

<p>Changes since snapshot 20:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Fix forking bug which caused snapshot 21 to lock up OS X</li>
  <li>The macvim color scheme changed so that line numbers look better when
    the background is dark (enable line numbers with :set number; set dark
    background with :set bg=dark)</li>
  <li>Improved support for Voice Over (enable with &lt;D-F5&gt;)</li>
  <li>System bell support (see :h 'vb' on how to turn it off)</li>
  <li>MacVim no longer associates to .plist and .dict since these may well be
    in binary format</li>
  <li>Added Find Next &lt;D-g&gt;, Find Previous &lt;D-G&gt; and Use Selection
    for Find &lt;D-e&gt; menu items</li>
  <li>Track pad scrolling is now force sensitive</li>
  <li>Added help section on preferences</li>
  <li>Preferences panel updated (also no longer hides when MacVim loses focus)
    </li>
</ul>

<p>The most exciting new addition in this snapshot is support for &lt;D-g&gt;.
It repeats the last search you made in any other application (that supports the
Find Pasteboard).</p>
<p>This is very useful if you have several windows open in MacVim...try
searching for something in one window (using "/"), then switching to another
window and hitting &lt;D-g&gt; for an example (after having pressed &lt;D-g&gt;
once you can of course use "n" to repeat the search).</p>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2008 19:36 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-22.tbz"
        length="7812907"
        sparkle:version="22"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="7.1"
        />
    </item>


    <item>
      <title>Snapshot 20 released</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
<h1>MacVim snapshot 20 released</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Automatic updates via Sparkle (Nico Weber)</li>
  <li>Preferences panel</li>
  <li>Fix ^C^W bug (Issue 48)</li>
  <li>Make sure window is ordered front when new files are opened</li>
  <li>Warn when quitting with multiple tabs or windows open</li>
  <li>&lt;D-w&gt; can now be used to close dialogs (such as the About dialog)</li>
</ul>
      ]]></description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Feb 2008 16:39 CET</pubDate>
      <enclosure type="application/octet-stream"
        url="http://macvim.googlecode.com/files/MacVim-snapshot-20.tbz"
        length="7805678"
        sparkle:version="20"
        sparkle:shortVersionString="snapshot 20"
        />
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
